<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Perspective</string>

    <string name="prompt">Choose a country</string>
    <string-array name="event_types">
        <item>Educational</item>
        <item>Social</item>
        <item>Professional</item>
        <item>Recreational</item>
        <item>Family</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>

    <string name = "timeout">How many times have you been told to ‘chill out,’  ‘chillax’ or ‘stop stressing’? These are everyday phrases but taking time to relax is really important to maintain positive mental health.\n\nFailing to take time to recharge your batteries and relax can contribute to some mental health problems such as anxiety or depression or make existing mental disorders worse. Relaxation therefore is key to maintaining positive mental wellbeing.\n\nWhether you are at school, college or working, things can get on top of us all at certain times and relaxation is vital to help our minds and bodies switch off from those pressures.\n\nHere are some Do’s and Dont’s\nDo:
    \n\nTake Up a Hobby - People who have stressful jobs often find that taking up a hobby can help them switch their brains off from work pressures once they are away from work. For example, if you are gaming, you are concentrating on what your fingers are doing rather than thinking about that essay that needs handing in next week that is stressing you out. Often when you go back to the thing that you were finding stressful, you can cope better having taken a break from it and switching off.
    \n\nGet Outside - Walking – walking also releases endorphins but can also help you to switch off from pressures as you take in the scenery around you and get into a steady rhythm  – and can be a far more pleasant way to travel than on a stuffy tube or busy loud bus which in itself can be stressful. Getting fresh air also helps you to relax and sleep better.
    \n\nYoga - yoga, tai chi and pilates are designed around relaxation and breathing techniques which can all aid relaxation.
    \n\nNetflix and Chill - Speaking literally, watching a film or reading a book – escapism is a great way to switch off from reality for a while and help the mind to relax. Pick a TV series or movie and have some ‘you time’, you earned it.\n\nDon’t:
    \nTake up smoking
    \nStart taking drugs
    \nDrink far more than you normally would</string>

    <string name ="posreinforce">Positive ReinforcementPositive ReinforcementPositive ReinforcementPositive ReinforcementPositive Reinforcement</string>

    <string name = "breathing">When you find yourself suddenly overwhelmed, most of us will allow ourselves to get more and more stressed. That wont help.\n\nIf you start to get a faster heartbeat or sweating palms, the best thing is not to fight it. Stay where you are and simply feel the panic without trying to distract yourself. Place the palm of your hand on your stomach and breathe slowly and deeply. The goal is to help the mind get used to coping with panic, which takes the fear of fear away.\nThe 4-7-8 breathing technique is broken down into three stages that you can follow;\n\n
    \t1) Breath in deeply for four seconds.\n
    \t2) Hold that breath for seven seconds.\n
    \t3) Fully exhale for eight seconds.\n\nRepeat as neccessary, this technique is also effective for when you find it difficult to fall asleep at the end of a long day.\n\nYou will get the most benefit if you do it regularly, as part of your daily routine.
You can do it standing up, sitting in a chair that supports your back, or lying on a bed or yoga mat on the floor.
Make yourself as comfortable as you can. If you can, loosen any clothes that restrict your breathing.</string>

    <string name="meditation">Feel like your brain is running on a constant loop of farfetched ‘what if’ scenarios? That’s the natural line of thinking of someone struggling with stress, anxiety or depression.\nTry these out to help you along the way to mindfulness.\n\nAnchoring\nOne of the best ways to calm yourself down is to anchor yourself by directing your attention into the lower half of your body. Begin by focusing on your feet and how they feel inside your socks or shoes and against the ground. Expand your attention to include the sensations first in your lower legs and then in your upper legs – do they feel heavy or light? Warm or cool? Tingly or numb? Now include the sensations of your breathing, really relaxing as you breathe out.\nThis is a great way of anchoring yourself and you can do it any time, with your eyes open or closed, while sitting or even while walking around. Anchor yourself. Then breathe.\n\nBreath Counting\nThis technique can be used in conjunction with anchoring or on its own. Anchor first. On your next in-breath, count up to 6 as you breathe all the way in, and then on the out-breath, count up to 10 as you breathe all the way out. This technique has the effect of lengthening both the in-breath and the out-breath, slowing down your breathing. It also lengthens the out-breath more than the in-breath, forcing you to release more carbon dioxide, slowing your heart rate, calming you down and restoring emotional equilibrium.\nMake sure you fit the numbers to your breath and not the other way around. If 6 and 10 don’t work for you, find another ratio that does, as long as the out-breath is at least two counts longer than the in-breath. If it’s too hard to continue breathing while counting, count for one full breath, then take one normal breath and count the next one.\nIf you feel very panicked and can’t manage the counting, say “in” to your self as you breath in, and “out” as you breathe out fully, trying to elongate the out-breath. Then again, say “in” on the in breath etc. Keep going for at least one minute but go for as long as you need. I have used this technique very successfully myself to ward off impending panic attacks in the middle of the night.\n\nFinger Breathing\nFinger breathing is another version of breath counting. Hold one hand in front of you, palm facing towards you. With the index finger of your other hand, trace up the outside length of your thumb while you breath in, pausing at the top of your thumb and then trace it down the other side while you breath out. That’s one breath. Trace up the side of the next finger while you breathe in, pause at the top, and then trace down the other side of that finger while you breathe out. That’s two breaths. Keep going, tracing along each finger as you count each breath. When you get the end of the last finger, come back up that finger and do it in reverse.\nThis practice gives you something visual to focus on and something kinaesthetic to do with your hands as well as focusing on counting and your breathing. Its very useful when there is a lot going around you and its hard to just close your eyes and focus inwards. It’s also a very easy technique to teach teenagers and kids.\n\nThe awesome thing about these mindfulness techniques is that you do not need to go anywhere to do them. In the middle of a lecture? At your desk? Out with friends? Go for it.</string>
</resources>
